{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Electricity may be generated by a wire:", "opta": "carrying current", "optb": "wrapped as a coil", "optc": "that has neutral domains", "optd": "passing through a flux field", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the given circuit, what will the voltage be across R3 25 s after the switch is moved to position 2?", "opta": "2.88 V", "optb": "5.9 V", "optc": "8.34 V", "optd": "14 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The electrical energy consumed by a coil is stored in the form of:", "opta": "an electrical field", "optb": "a force field", "optc": "an electrostatic field", "optd": "a magnetic field", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is magnetic flux?", "opta": "the number of lines of force in webers", "optb": "the number of lines of force in maxwells", "optc": "the number of lines of force in teslas", "optd": "the number of lines of force in flux density", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "As current travels within a conductor:", "opta": "the magnetic field aids the current", "optb": "a magnetic field is developed around it", "optc": "the wire tries to point north", "optd": "an electrostatic field opposes the current", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What type of device consists of a coil with a moveable iron core?", "opta": "solenoid", "optb": "reed switch", "optc": "relay", "optd": "armature", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is hysteresis?", "opta": "lead between cause and effect", "optb": "lag between cause and effect", "optc": "lead between voltage and current", "optd": "lag between voltage and current", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a purely inductive circuit,", "opta": "current leads voltage by 90\u00b0", "optb": "voltage lags current by 90\u00b0", "optc": "voltage leads current by 90\u00b0", "optd": "voltage and current are in phase (0\u00b0)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A series RL filter circuit with an output across the inductor will result in what type of filtering?", "opta": "passing of the higher frequencies", "optb": "passing of the lower frequencies", "optc": "blocking of the higher frequencies", "optd": "blocking of a certain range of frequencies", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the total inductance in the given circuit?", "opta": "160 mH", "optb": "300 mH", "optc": "900 mH", "optd": "1700 mH", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "On a schematic, dashed lines between two vertical coils usually mean the transformer has:", "opta": "an air core", "optb": "an iron core", "optc": "a nonmetallic core", "optd": "a ferrite core", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Faraday's law states that the:", "opta": "direction of the induced voltage produces an opposition", "optb": "direction of an induced current produces an aiding effect", "optc": "emf depends on the rate of cutting flux", "optd": "emf is related to the direction of the current", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A henry value divided by a circuit resistive value provides the:", "opta": "counter emf value", "optb": "induced voltage amplitude", "optc": "rise or decay time constant", "optd": "quality factor of the coil", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What does Faraday's law concern?", "opta": "a magnetic field in a coil", "optb": "a magnetic field cutting a conductor", "optc": "a magnetic field hystersis", "optd": "a magnetic field in a conductor", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The polarity of induced voltage while a field is collapsing is:", "opta": "independent of the force creating it", "optb": "opposite to the force creating it", "optc": "identical to the force creating the field", "optd": "present only if the force is stationary", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the permeability of transformer iron?", "opta": "50", "optb": "450", "optc": "1,500", "optd": "5,500", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Electromagnetism is the:", "opta": "magnetic field caused by a permanent magnet", "optb": "action between a permanent and an artificial magnet", "optc": "magnetic field action with a current-carrying wire", "optd": "current in the coil", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A magnetic field has:", "opta": "polar fields", "optb": "lines of force", "optc": "magnetomotive force", "optd": "lines of reluctance", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which two values are plotted on a B-H curve graph?", "opta": "reluctance and flux density", "optb": "permeability and reluctance", "optc": "magnetizing force and permeability", "optd": "flux density and magnetizing force", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the number of turns required in the secondary winding for a transformer when 120 volts is applied to a 2400-turn primary to produce 7.5 Vac at the secondary?", "opta": "75 turns", "optb": "150 turns", "optc": "900 turns", "optd": "1920 turns", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The four factors determining inductance are the number of turns, coil length, coil area, and:", "opta": "permeability", "optb": "reluctance", "optc": "counter emf", "optd": "coefficient of coupling", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the inductive reactance if the Q of a coil is 60, and the winding resistance is 5 ?", "opta": "0.083", "optb": "12", "optc": "30", "optd": "300", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The time difference, or lag, between flux density and magnetizing force is known as:", "opta": "eddy current", "optb": "magnetic saturation", "optc": "hysteresis", "optd": "coercivity", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A magnetic circuit breaker will open to protect equipment only when:", "opta": "voltage is exceeded", "optb": "an open is in the equipment", "optc": "the equipment is operating properly", "optd": "current is exceeded", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Electromagnetic induction is the generation of:", "opta": "electricity from magnetism", "optb": "electricity from electricity", "optc": "magnetism from electricity", "optd": "magnetism from magnetism", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Inductance is:", "opta": "directly proportional to the length of the coil", "optb": "directly proportional to the number of turns on the coil", "optc": "inversely proportional to the cross-sectional area of the coil", "optd": "inversely proportional to the permeability", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Current will cause a magnetic field in a conductor as follows:", "opta": "An ac current causes a fixed polarity magnetic field.", "optb": "A dc current causes a fixed polarity magnetic field.", "optc": "A dc current causes an alternating magnetic field.", "optd": "An ac current causes a fixed polarity magnetic field and a dc current causes an alternating magnetic field.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the total inductance, assuming no mutual inductance?", "opta": "12 mH", "optb": "6 mH", "optc": "0.73 mH", "optd": "0 mH", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "During a current change, the ability of a conductor to produce counter emf within itself is called:", "opta": "back emf", "optb": "self-induction", "optc": "a henry", "optd": "impedance", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the switch is moved to position 1 in the given circuit, how long will it take for the current to reach its maximum value?", "opta": "72.5 s", "optb": "532 s", "optc": "610 s", "optd": "833 s", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a transformer secondary lead has been connected to a middle loop that is not an end connector, it is called a:", "opta": "multiple-tapped secondary", "optb": "center-tapped secondary", "optc": "multiple winding secondary", "optd": "single winding secondary", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A 24 V peak source is connected across a 900 H inductor. If the frequency of the source is 22 kHz, what is the reactive power?", "opta": "2.3 VAR", "optb": "4.6 VAR", "optc": "9.3 VAR", "optd": "0 VAR", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the permeability of machine steel?", "opta": "1.1 x 10\u22124", "optb": "5.65 x 10\u22124", "optc": "6.9 x 10\u22123", "optd": "8.8 x 10\u22123", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What will happen when an inductor's magnetic field collapses?", "opta": "Current will double.", "optb": "Voltage will be induced.", "optc": "A new field will expand.", "optd": "Counter emf will be high.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With a square wave input, an RL differentiator circuit with an output across the inductor will produce what type of waveform?", "opta": "dc", "optb": "short time-duration pulses", "optc": "exponential-shaped pulses", "optd": "only a phase shift", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How long until the current is at a maximum?", "opta": "0 s", "optb": "5 s", "optc": "15 s", "optd": "25 s", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Find VR and VL.", "opta": "VR = 41.6 V, VL = 78.4 V", "optb": "VR = 48 V, VL = 110 V", "optc": "VR = 56 V, VL = 106 V", "optd": "VR = 60 V, VL = 60 V", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If 360 Vac is the output of a 300-turn secondary winding, what is the input voltage when the primary winding has 150 turns?", "opta": "2.4 Vac", "optb": "150 Vac", "optc": "180 Vac", "optd": "720 Vac", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a magnet enters a coil and a voltage is induced, the process is known as:", "opta": "an alternation", "optb": "self-inductance", "optc": "counter emf", "optd": "flux linkage", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What term is used to describe the action of magnetic flux from one circuit that cuts across the conductors of another circuit?", "opta": "self-inductance", "optb": "rectification", "optc": "mutual inductance", "optd": "magnetism", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Reactance in an inductive circuit will:", "opta": "increase with frequency", "optb": "decrease with frequency", "optc": "be independent from frequency", "optd": "depend on the value of XC", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A turns ratio of 5 for a transformer implies:", "opta": "more primary turns than secondary turns", "optb": "more secondary current than primary current", "optc": "larger source impedance than load impedance", "optd": "more secondary turns than primary turns", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A practical inductor", "opta": "has inductance", "optb": "has winding resistance", "optc": "has winding capacitance", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When current in an inductor starts to change, it cannot react instantly due to:", "opta": "fixed coil resistance", "optb": "eddy current generation", "optc": "applied emf of the circuit", "optd": "the counter emf of the coil", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the approximate time for a complete decay of 400 mA of inductor current, when R = 10 ohms and L = 20 H?", "opta": "10 seconds", "optb": "8 seconds", "optc": "4 seconds", "optd": "2 seconds", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A utility pole transformer used to supply a residential customer with two phases uses:", "opta": "two phases on the primary", "optb": "a center tap on the secondary", "optc": "a separate ground for each phase", "optd": "a small coefficient of coupling", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the inductive reactance?", "opta": "5.2", "optb": "7.5", "optc": "1.3 k", "optd": "7.5 k", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a coil collapses the induced circuit current will:", "opta": "be in the same direction", "optb": "go to zero", "optc": "aid counter emf buildup", "optd": "be in the opposite direction", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a rate of one ampere per second causes an induced voltage of one volt, the unit of measure is", "opta": "a lenz", "optb": "an ohm", "optc": "a farad", "optd": "a henry", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If you wanted to decrease the inductance of a coil, you might increase the:", "opta": "number of turns", "optb": "permeability of the core", "optc": "spacing between turns", "optd": "area of the coil", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The output phase for a transformer is:", "opta": "in phase with the input", "optb": "out of phase with the input", "optc": "dependent on the direction of the primary and secondary windings", "optd": "dependent on the frequency of the primary source", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Opposition to current flow without the dissipation of energy is called:", "opta": "resistance", "optb": "inductive reactance", "optc": "counter emf", "optd": "impedance", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With 100 Vac applied to the primary of a transformer so that it draws 500 mA, what will be the 300 Vac secondary current?", "opta": "1500 mA", "optb": "200 mA", "optc": "167 mA", "optd": "150 mA", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which coil would be used as a step-up transformer primary if coil number 1 has 100 more turns than coil number 2?", "opta": "The coil windings must be the same.", "optb": "coil 1", "optc": "The coil ratio is too small.", "optd": "coil 2", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Find IR and IL.", "opta": "IR = 50 mA, IL = 109 mA", "optb": "IR = 150 mA, IL = 9 mA", "optc": "IR = 50 mA, IL = 151 mA", "optd": "IR = 150 mA, IL = 53 mA", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When the transformer secondary is not loaded:", "opta": "secondary voltage increases", "optb": "no secondary current flows", "optc": "no secondary voltage is present", "optd": "secondary current increases", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the current rise after 2 time constants if Vs = 12 V dc, R = 60 , and the inductor is rated at 24 mH?", "opta": "79.9 mA", "optb": "126.4 mA", "optc": "173.0 mA", "optd": "198.6 mA", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the total inductance of a 5 H and a 100 mH coil connected in parallel?", "opta": "4.76 mH", "optb": "33.3 mH", "optc": "98.0 mH", "optd": "150.0 mH", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A transformer is used:", "opta": "to couple electric energy from one dc circuit to another", "optb": "to couple electric energy from an ac circuit to a dc circuit", "optc": "to couple electric energy from a dc circuit to an ac circuit", "optd": "to couple electric energy from one ac circuit to another", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is NOT one of the three major types of fixed inductor?", "opta": "air core", "optb": "ferrite core", "optc": "magnesium core", "optd": "iron core", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the impedance of a 1 kHz series RL circuit when R and XL are both 1000 ohms?", "opta": "500 ohms", "optb": "1000 ohms", "optc": "1414 ohms", "optd": "2000 ohms", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is remanence?", "opta": "reactance", "optb": "reluctance", "optc": "retentitivity", "optd": "resistance", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When an electromagnet reaches maximum strength, it is considered to be:", "opta": "in field condition", "optb": "at saturation", "optc": "inhibited", "optd": "at field strength", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "You could decrease the time constant of an RL circuit by", "opta": "adding a resistor in parallel with the circuit resistance", "optb": "adding an inductor in series with the circuit inductance", "optc": "decreasing the amplitude of the input voltage", "optd": "exchanging the position of the resistor and inductor in the circuit", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Indication of transformer primary and secondary voltage relationships is accomplished by:", "opta": "color-coded wires", "optb": "dot notation", "optc": "black, rather than gray, casings", "optd": "winding ratios", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "As a generator armature passes the 270 degree point, the induced voltage is:", "opta": "at maximum negative", "optb": "between maximum negative and zero", "optc": "at maximum positive", "optd": "between zero and maximum positive", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A value of \"ten to the eighth power magnetic lines of force\" is for the term:", "opta": "field", "optb": "flux", "optc": "coulomb", "optd": "weber", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A change of one ampere per second in an inductor that induces a voltage of one volt is considered as which unit value?", "opta": "a lenz", "optb": "an ohm", "optc": "a farad", "optd": "a henry", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the name of the part inside a relay that is moved by the action of the electromagnet?", "opta": "armature", "optb": "conductor", "optc": "contacts", "optd": "solenoid", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the primary of a 4:1 turns transformer dissipates 5 W, what is the secondary power?", "opta": "5.0 W", "optb": "1.25 pW", "optc": "9.5 W", "optd": "20.0 mW", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The unit of flux density is:", "opta": "magnetomotive force", "optb": "a weber", "optc": "a maxwell", "optd": "a tesla", "ans": "D", "explanation": "tesla or weber/m2 is the unit of flux density"}, {"question": "When used as a filter, an inductor is", "opta": "placed in series with the load and aids any current changes", "optb": "placed in parallel with the load and aids any current changes", "optc": "placed in parallel with the load and opposes any current changes", "optd": "placed in series with the load and opposes any current changes", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A loaded transformer will achieve mutual induction when:", "opta": "secondary current increase causes a primary current decrease", "optb": "primary current is increased by an increase in secondary current", "optc": "primary current is decreased by an increase in secondary current", "optd": "secondary current decrease causes a primary current increase", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which transformer turns ratio is needed to match two 16-ohm parallel devices to an output of 22.2 ohms?", "opta": "1.38:1", "optb": "1.67:1", "optc": "0.72:1", "optd": "0.60:1", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A transformer will have:", "opta": "primary and secondary windings", "optb": "primary and secondary current", "optc": "primary wattage producing secondary current", "optd": "different frequencies for the primary and secondary", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the phase angle of a 24 Vac parallel RL circuit when R = 45 ohms and XL = 1100 ohms?", "opta": "0.001 degrees", "optb": "2.300 degrees", "optc": "87.600 degrees", "optd": "89.900 degrees", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A winding of wire can be called", "opta": "an inductor", "optb": "a coil", "optc": "a choke", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What happens when moving expanding lines of force encounter a conductor?", "opta": "Current increases.", "optb": "Voltage is induced.", "optc": "Resistance is reduced.", "optd": "Power is increased.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fixed transformers have:", "opta": "a center-tapped secondary", "optb": "multiple windings", "optc": "turns ratios that cannot be changed", "optd": "a multiple-tapped secondary", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a B-H curve, magnetizing force is equal to:", "opta": "", "optb": "H = I \u00d7 N", "optc": "ampere-turns per weber", "optd": "webers per square meter", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following represents a true equivalent of an inductor?", "opta": "An inductance in series with a resistance and a capacitance", "optb": "A capacitance in parallel with the series combination of a resistance and an inductance", "optc": "An inductance in parallel with the series combination of a resistance and a capacitance", "optd": "The only quality a real inductor has is inductance.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a transformer, what will happen to the primary current if the secondary magnetic field increases?", "opta": "Ip will increase.", "optb": "Ip will be canceled.", "optc": "Ip will remain the same.", "optd": "Ip will decrease.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The time required for one weber of flux to cut a conductor and produce one volt is:", "opta": "one revolution", "optb": "one second", "optc": "one millisecond", "optd": "four revolutions", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the maximum source current for a transformer rated at 10 kVA, 1000/500 60 Hz?", "opta": "2 A", "optb": "5 A", "optc": "10 A", "optd": "20 A", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the total inductance assuming no mutual inductance?", "opta": "0 mH", "optb": "0.69 mH", "optc": "12 mH", "optd": "24 mH", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A voltage is induced in a transformer secondary winding by the action of the:", "opta": "secondary magnetic field", "optb": "primary turns ratio", "optc": "primary magnetic field", "optd": "secondary counter emf", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is electromagnetism?", "opta": "the magnetic field generated around a conductor when a current passes through it", "optb": "the magnetic field generated in a conductor by an external voltage", "optc": "the voltage caused by a magnetic field in a conductor", "optd": "the current generated by an external magnetic field", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Counter emf or induced voltage is:", "opta": "inversely proportional to the change in current", "optb": "directly proportional to the change in time", "optc": "directly proportional to the inductance in henrys", "optd": "inversely proportional to the inductance in henrys", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are the properties that determine the inductance of a coil?", "opta": "Length of wire, number of turns, type of core material, length of core", "optb": "Number of turns, type of wire, length of core, and cross-sectional area of core", "optc": "Type of core material, number of turns, cross-sectional area of core, and length of core", "optd": "Type of core material, type of wire, number of turns, and cross-sectional area of core", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An inductor is in series with a voltage source, an open switch, and a resistor. The instant the switch is closed, the inductor acts like", "opta": "a short", "optb": "an open", "optc": "a resistor", "optd": "a voltage source", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the phase angle between the source voltage and current, when a 100 mH inductor with a reactance of 6 k, and a 1 k resistor are in series with a source?", "opta": "0.1 degrees", "optb": "9.0 degrees", "optc": "61.0 degrees", "optd": "81.0 degrees", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a load is not connected to the secondary of a transformer:", "opta": "primary current is zero", "optb": "primary current is inversely proportional to primary impedance", "optc": "secondary voltage is zero", "optd": "secondary voltage is proportional to primary impedance", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}